Etsegenet Mengistu

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

(571) 926-2778 | etsemengistu22@gmail.com | Lorton, VA linkedin.com/in/Etsegenet-L | https://github.com/Leyou14

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a passionate **web developer** with 6+ months of hands-on experience as a Junior **Front-End Developer**, I possess technical skills in **React**, **JavaScript**, **HTML**, **CSS**, and more. Currently participating in the 11-week, 350+ hour Generation Junior Web Developer Program, I am gaining practical experience in programming fundamentals, **developer tools**, and problem-solving. With a dedication to quality and a self-motivated work ethic, I am excited to continue growing and developing my skills in web development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

W3Schools JavaScript Certification (in progress; expected date of completion 06/2023)

HTML

CSS

React.Js

MySQL

Node.js

Bootstrap

Unit Testing with

Mocha

TailwindCSS

EXPERIENCE

Seminaut Digital Solutions | San Marcos, TX | Oct 2022- present

Position Title- Junior Front-End Developer

- Successfully completed assigned projects within stipulated timelines mostly every 2 weeks by developing and implementing efficient code.
- Developed a showcase feature that allows users to add their favorite items by utilizing
 React hooks and API calls to obtain user data and update the system in real-time, thereby
 enhancing the user experience, improved user engagement and retention
- Utilized **Figma** to design a partial social media page, including the development of a live feed section that improved the user experience.
- Collaborated with team members to identify and troubleshoot software bugs, resulting in a more stable and efficient product.
- Implemented **responsive design** principles to ensure that applications were accessible user-friendly across a variety of devices and screen sizes.

Generation Junior Web Developer Program | Mar 2023- June 2023

- Participating in an 11-week, 350+ hour Junior Web Developer program that emphasizes hands-on practical application
- Learning fundamentals of JavaScript, programming fundamentals, developer tools, git and problem solving

EDUCATION

Generation USA | March 2023-June 2023 | Junior Web Development

JavaScript Certificate W3Schools

Evangadi Tech. | Jan2022- Jul2022 | Full-Stack Web Development

• Certificate of Completion

Addis Ababa University | Sep 2016 - June 2019 | Marketing Management

• Masters Degree